Shallow Water. Deep Secret.
The Cove is a documentary film directed by Louie Psihoyos.
The Cove tells the amazing true story of how an elite team of individuals, films makers and free divers embarked on
a covert mission to penetrate the hidden cove in Japan, shining light on a dark and deadly secret.
The shocking discoveries were only the tip of the iceberg.
Self, played by Hayden Panettiere.
Self, played by Joe Chisholm.
Self, played by Mandy-Rae Cruikshank.
Self, played by Charles Hambleton.
Self, played by Simon Hutchins.
Self, played by Kirk Krack.
The Cove is a 2009 American documentary film directed by Louie Psihoyos that
analyzes and questions dolphin hunting practices in Japan.
It was awarded the Academy Award for Best Documentary Feature in 2010.
The film is a call to action to halt mass dolphin kills and captures, change Japanese fishing practices, and inform and
educate the public about captivity and the increasing hazard of mercury poisoning from consuming dolphin meat.
Psihoyos is a former-National Geographic photographer and a co-founder of the Oceanic Preservation
Society, and the film is presented from an ocean conservationist's point of view.
Portions were filmed secretly in 2007 using underwater microphones
and high-definition cameras disguised as rocks.
The film highlights the fact that the number of dolphins killed in the Taiji dolphin drive hunt is several times greater than the number of whales
killed in the Antarctic, and asserts that 23,000 dolphins and porpoises are killed in Japan every year by the country's whaling industry.
The migrating dolphins are herded into a cove where they are netted off.
The young and pretty are sold to oceanariums and dolphinariums
around the world, and the rest are brutally slaughtered.
The film argues that dolphin hunting as practiced
in Japan is unnecessary and cruel.
Since the film's release, The Cove has drawn controversy over its supposed lack of
neutrality, secret filming techniques,  and accusations of anti-Japanese sentiment.
Nevertheless, the film received predominantly positive reviews from critics.
It won the U.S.
Audience Award at the 25th annual Sundance Film Festival in January 2009.
It was selected out of 879 submissions in the category.
The film explores themes of dying and death, japan, suffering, ocean, dolphin.
The tone is dark.